<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Waver</string>

    <string name="howtoknife">Before any spells, you must learn to wield a weapon. Physical violence may be the last resort, but many a wizard owes their life to combat training. Take this knife, and let me see a few practice stabs.</string>
    <string name="howtoknife2">Starting from the lower part of the screen, slide your finger straight up. </string>
    <string name="howtoknifepass1">Good. Let me see another attack.</string>
    <string name="howtoknifepass2">Well done. Observe running your finger up the left half means your stab is left-handed; similarly, sliding up the right half of the screen causes a right-handed stab.</string>
    <string name="howtoknifepass3">Excellent. Let us move on.</string> 

    <string name="dummytut">Stab this wooden dummy 3 times to destroy it. Use the motion you just learned, then tap the bottom of the screen to confirm each stab.</string>
    <string name="dummytut1">Notice you cannot stab with both hands simultaneously. You only have one knife; you can only stab once per turn.</string>
    <string name="dummytutwin">Good job. Beware! You will face armed and dangerous monsters in the next lesson.</string>
    <string name="dummytutdraw">Very funny, though strictly speaking you did destroy the dummy. You're lucky I know the Raise Dead spell. Clearly you know how to play, so we'll skip a lesson. </string>
    <string name="dummytutlose">Very funny. You're lucky I know the Raise Dead spell. We'll move on, even though you lost to a wooden dummy.</string>

    <string name="targettut">Did you notice the green line indicating the target? In this fight, you must direct your first stabs to the goblins, who each inflict one point of damage. Drag your finger from the Stab icon to a goblin before ending your turn. </string>
    <string name="targettutwin">Capital! At last you are ready to learn magic. The first gesture you'll learn is the easiest, but also the most powerful.</string>
    <string name="targettutdraw">Close enough. Let's move on anyway. The first gesture you'll learn is the easiest, but also the most powerful.</string>
    <string name="targettutlose">You're lucky I know the Raise Dead spell. Let's try that again.</string>
    
    <string name="shieldtut">The Palm gesture (P) is performed by dragging your finger down the screen, starting in the lower section. It's the opposite of the Knife gesture. A single Palm will cast the Shield spell, which protects you from all physical attacks, such as stabs and monsters.
    </string>
    <string name="shieldtut2">But be warned! Due to its power, gesturing Palm with both hands causes you to lose at the end of the round, unless you have simultaneously vanquished your opponent.</string>
</resources>
