<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Spell Tap</string>

    <string name="academynag">Tap on the Academy.</string>

    <string name="welcome">So you want to be a wizard? And partake in duels of sorcery? Then listen carefully... </string>
    <string name="howtoknife">Before any spells, you must learn to wield your knife. Physical violence may be the last resort, but many a wizard owes their life to combat training.</string>
    <string name="howtoknife2">Starting from the lower part of the screen, slide your finger up ( &#x2191; ). </string>
    <string name="howtoknifepass1">Good stab! Do it again.</string>
    <string name="howtoknifepass2">Observe using the left half of the screen gives a left-handed stab, and using the right half gives a right-handed stab.</string>
    <string name="howtoknifepass3">Excellent. Let\'s go find a target.</string>

    <string name="dummytut">Stab the wooden dummy 3 times to destroy it. Use the motion you just learned, then tap the bottom of the screen to confirm each stab.</string>
    <string name="dummytutwin">Well done. Let\'s see how you handle hostile targets.</string>
    <string name="dummytutdraw">Very funny, though strictly speaking you did destroy the dummy. You\'re lucky I know the Raise Dead spell. Clearly you know how to play, so we\'ll skip a lesson. </string>
    <string name="dummytutlose">Very funny. You\'re lucky I know the Raise Dead spell. We\'ll move on, even though you lost to a wooden dummy.</string>

    <string name="targettut">You must direct your first stabs to the goblins, who each inflict one point of damage. Make a Knife gesture, then drag your finger from the Stab icon to a goblin. </string>
    <string name="targettutwin">At last you are ready to learn magic. The first gesture you\'ll learn is the easiest, but also the most powerful.</string>
    <string name="targettutlose">You\'re lucky I know the Raise Dead spell. Let\'s try that again.</string>

    <string name="palmtut">Drag your finger downwards ( &#x2193; ) in the lower part of the screen to make the Palm gesture (P). </string>
    <string name="palmtutpass1">Good, try another Palm.</string>
    <string name="palmtutpass2">Good, try another Palm.</string>
    <string name="palmtutpass3">That\'s plenty for now.</string>

    <string name="shieldtut">The Shield spell can be cast with a single Palm. Shield protects you from all physical attacks.</string>

    <string name="shieldtut2">Beware! Gesturing Palm with both hands means you surrender: you lose at the end of the round, unless your opponent is dead.</string>
    <string name="shieldtut3">Sendin is your next opponent. Cast Shield to block his stabs.</string>
    <string name="shieldtutdraw">A draw is not good enough. With the Shield spell you should be able to win easily.</string>
    <string name="shieldtutwin">Well done. Let's pick up the pace.</string>
    <string name="shieldtutlose">Let\'s try it again, shall we?</string>

    <string name="SDtut">Do a Snap gesture (S) by drawing a diagonally up and away from the center, like a Knife gesture that veers outwards (L: &#x2196; R: &#x2197; ). Make Snap with both hands and end your turn.</string>
    <string name="SDtutpass1">Now, the Digit gesture (D) is the same except you go toward to center (L: &#x2197; R: &#x2196; ). Make Digit with both hands and end the turn.</string>
    <string name="SDtutpass2">Surprise! S followed by D casts Missile. Unlike Shield, most spells take several turns to cast.</string>

    <string name="wavetut">To make a Wave gesture (W), run your finger diagonally downwards and away from the center (L: &#x2199; R: &#x2198; ). Wave both hands and end your turn.</string>
    <string name="fingerstut">Now make the Fingers gesture (F) on both hands: run a finger diagonally downwards and towards the center (L: &#x2198; R: &#x2199; ). Then end your turn.</string>
    <string name="fingerstutpass1">Perfect! Now gesture Palm with both hands. Normally this loses, but since WFP is Cause Light Wounds, you can do 4 points of damage to kill your opponent.</string>
    <string name="fingerstutpass2">If you kill the opponent, you win even if you gesture Palm with both hands.</string>
    <string name="fingerstutpass3">One more thing. A single gesture can only complete one spell, so you must choose Cause Light Wounds over Shield by tapping its icon.</string>
    <string name="fingerstutpass4">Well done! Cause Light Wounds deals 2 damage even to shielded targets.</string>
    <string name="fingerstutfail">Almost. Try again.</string>

    <string name="PKfighttut">Your next opponent always tries to cast Shield on himself. </string>
    <string name="PKfighttut2"> Cause Light Wounds (WFP) may help. Another handy spell is Confusion (DSF): its target must gesture identically with both hands. Good luck!</string>
    <string name="PKfighttutwin">Impressive!</string>
    <string name="PKfighttutlose">This is a tough fight. Don\'t lose heart!</string>
    <string name="PKfighttutdraw">I\'ll let you pass, but remember you won\'t always have someone around to cast Raise Dead on you.</string>

</resources>
