<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Spell Tap</string>

<string name="town0">Welcome to Spell Tap!\n[Tap the screen to continue.]</string>
<string name="town1">You\'ve travelled for days, but your journey has just begun. At last, you stand before the world\'s top magic academy: The School of Thought.\n[Tap the screen to continue.]</string>
    <string name="academynag">[Tap on the academy.]</string>
    <string name="academynag2">[Tap the academy again to enter.]</string>

    <string name="welcome">So you want to be a wizard? And partake in duels of sorcery? Then listen carefully...</string>
    <string name="howtoknife">Before any spells, you must learn to wield your <b>Knife</b>. Physical violence may be the last resort, but many a wizard owes their life to combat training. I will first teach you to <i>Stab</i>.</string>
    <string name="howtoknife2">Starting from the lower left of the screen, slide your finger up ( &#x2191; ).</string>
    <string name="howtoknifepass1">That\'s certainly a <b>Knife</b>! Try stabbing on the right side.</string>
    <string name="howtoknifepass2">Good! Gesturing on the left half of the screen gives a left-handed <i>Stab</i>, and the right half gives a right-handed <i>Stab</i>.</string>
    <string name="howtoknifeonemore">Try another left hand <i>Stab</i>.</string>
    <string name="howtoknifepass3">You show promise. Wait for me at the training hall.</string>

<string name="jackwaitsatdummy">Jack awaits you at the training hall.</string>

    <string name="dummytut"><i>Stab</i> this wooden dummy 3 times to destroy it.</string>
    <string name="dummytut1">Do the <b>K</b> (<b>Knife</b>) gesture in either hand.</string>
    <string name="dummytut2">Now tap the bottom of the screen.</string>
    <string name="dummytut3">Nice! Repeat to finish off the dummy.</string>
    <string name="dummytutwin">Well done. But let\'s see how you handle hostile targets.</string>
    <string name="dummytutdraw">Very funny, though strictly speaking you did destroy the dummy. You\'re lucky I know the Raise Dead spell.</string>
    <string name="dummytutlose">Very funny. You\'re lucky I know the Raise Dead spell. We\'ll move on, even though you lost to a wooden dummy.</string>
    <string name="dummytutskip">Clearly you know how to target your spells, so we\'ll skip a lesson. Train more on the dummy, If you like. Then see me back at school for your first magic lesson.</string>

    <string name="targettut">Again, do the <i>Knife</i> gesture.</string>
    <string name="targettut1">Next, direct your attack to a goblin. Drag your finger from the <i>Stab</i> icon to a goblin. [Tap to continue.]</string>
    <string name="targettut2">Now tap the bottom of the screen.</string>
    <string name="targettut3">Good! Kill the other goblin, then destroy the dummy.</string>
    <string name="targettutwin">You learn fast. Come see me at the school for your first magic lesson. Or stay awhile and smash a few more dummies.</string>
    <string name="targettutlose">You\'re lucky I know the <i>Raise Dead</i> spell. Let\'s try that again.</string>

    <string name="palmtut"><b>Palm</b> is a simple but powerful magical gesture.</string>
    <string name="palmtut1">Drag your finger downwards ( &#x2193; ) in the lower part of the screen to make the <b>Palm</b> gesture (<b>P</b>). </string>
    <string name="palmtutpass1">Good. In a duel, you could cast <i><i>Shield</i></i> now. Try <b>P</b> on other side.</string>
    <string name="palmtutpass2">Great! <i>Shield</i> protects you from all physical attacks. Do one more <b>P</b>. Switch hands again.</string>
    <string name="palmtutpass3">Excellent! But beware! Gesturing <b>P</b> with both hands means you surrender!</string>
    <string name="palmtutpass4">Double <b>P</b> loses, unless your opponent dies.</string>
    <string name="palmtutpass5">Your first opponent awaits you at the Arena. See me once you\'ve won.</string>

<string name="duel1advice1">Cast <i>Shield</i> (<b>P</b>) to block stabs.</string>
<string name="duel1advice2">If you end up in trouble, surrender by gesturing <b>P</b> with both hands.</string>
<string name="duel1advice3">Good luck! See you after the duel!</string>

    <string name="arenashut">The Arena is closed.</string>

    <string name="SDtut0">Well fought! Let\'s pick up the pace.</string>
    <string name="SDtut1">A <b>Snap</b> gesture (<b>S</b>) goes diagonally up and away from the center, like a <b>Knife</b> gesture that veers outwards (L: &#x2196; R: &#x2197; ).</string>
    <string name="SDtut2">Make <b>Snap</b> with both hands.</string>
    <string name="SDtut3">Tap the bottom of the screen to confirm.</string>
    <string name="SDtutpass1">Next, the <b>Digit</b> gesture (<b>D</b>) is the same except you go toward to center (L: &#x2197; R: &#x2196; ).</string>
    <string name="SDtutpass100">Make <b>D</b> with both hands.</string>
    <string name="SDtutpass2">Surprise! <b>S</b> then <b>D</b> casts <i>Missile</i>. Unlike <i>Shield</i>, most spells take several turns to cast.</string>
    <string name="SDtutpass3">At any time, press [MENU] to access your spellbook and review all you have learned so far.</string>
    <string name="SDtutpass4">Have fun! Come find me later.</string>
    <string name="SDtutwrong">That\'s not right. Let\'s start again.</string>

    <string name="meetforwfp">Now, <i>Missile</i> is useful, but can be blocked by <i>Shield</i>.</string>
    <string name="meetforwfp2">I\'ll teach you <i>Cause Light Wounds</i>, which deals 2 damage even to shielded targets. Meet me at the Training Hall.</string>

    <string name="wavetut">To make a <b>Wave</b> gesture (<b>W</b>), run your finger diagonally downwards and away from the center (L: &#x2199; R: &#x2198; ).</string>
    <string name="wavetut1">Gesture <b>Wave</b> with both hands.</string>
    <string name="wavetut2">Tap the bottom of the screen</string>
    <string name="fingerstut">Now make the <b>Fingers</b> gesture (<b>F</b>) on both hands: run a finger diagonally downwards and towards the center (L: &#x2198; R: &#x2199; ).</string>
    <string name="fingerstutpass1">Perfect! Gesture <b>Palm</b> with both hands. Normally this loses, but since <b>WFP</b> is <i>Cause Light Wounds</i>, you\'ll do 4 points of damage and kill your opponent!</string>
    <string name="fingerstutpass2">Well done! Notice a gesture can only complete 1 spell, explaining why no <i>Shield</i> was cast.</string>
    <string name="fingerstutpass3">I\'ll see you back at school.</string>
    <string name="fingerstutfail">Almost. Try again.</string>

    <string name="DSFteach1"><b>DSF</b> casts <i>Confusion</i>. The victim must gesture identically with both hands next turn.</string>
    <string name="DSFteach2">Observe a confused opponent who gestures <b>P</b> must do so with both hands, and thus surrenders!</string>
    <string name="DSFteach3">Remember, press [MENU] to review all you have learned. Now head to the Arena, where your next foe awaits.</string>

    <string name="duel2advice1">Recall <i>Shield</i> blocks <i>Stab</i> and <i>Missile</i>.</string>
    <string name="duel2advice2">To deal with <i>Shield</i>, try <i>Cause Light Wounds</i> (<b>WFP</b>). The <i>Confusion</i> spell (<b>DSF</b>) may also help. Good luck!</string>

<string name="cureteach1">Impressive! You\'re ready for more spells.</string>
<string name="cureteach2"><b>DFW</b> is <i>Cure Light Wounds</i>, which restores up to one point of health.</string>
<string name="cureteach3">And <b>SFW</b> is <i>Summon Goblin</i>, which summons a goblin to fight for you.</string>
<string name="cureteach4">You encountered two goblins before. Each has 1 point of health and attacks for 1 damage.</string>

<string name="generic_advice">Best of luck in your next battle!</string>

    <string name="talkabouttilt1">There\'s a showier way to cast spells than tapping the bottom of the screen.</string>
    <string name="talkabouttilt2">After gesturing, tilt the screen up vertically. When the bottom line flashes, tilt the screen back to its original position.</string>

<string name="lvl1teach1">There are two more Level 1 spells. See your spellbook.</string>
<string name="lvl1teach2">
<b>WWP</b> is <i>Protection From Evil</i>. It acts as a Shield that lasts for 4 turns, including the turn it is cast.</string>
<string name="lvl1teach3"><b>PSDF</b> is <i>Charm Person</i>, which forces the opponent to make a gesture of your choice on one hand. It also cancels with <i>Confusion</i>.</string>
<string name="lvl1teach4">Your next challenger is waiting for you at the Arena. See me afterwards.</string>

<string name="graduate1">Congratulations! You are now a Level 1 Wizard!</string>
<string name="graduate2">Pick fights with other wizards at the Tavern, and
earn experience by casting spells in duels. Then gain levels and learn new spells.</string>
<string name="graduate3">No doubt you found yourself disadvantaged whenever you failed to select a gesture for one or both hands.</string>
<string name="graduate4">From now on, this game will help you by insisting you have a gesture in each hand.</string>

<string name="lvl2teach1">Welcome to Level 2! Your Summon spells are now stronger.</string>
<string name="lvl2teach2">Monsters can attack the turn they are summoned. Spells may also target monsters as they materialize.</string>
<string name="lvl2teach3">Experiment with the summoning circles to see what I mean.</string>

<string name="bug">Oops! You\'ve uncovered a bug!</string>
<string name="win">You win!</string>
<string name="lose">You lose...</string>
<string name="draw">You both die. It\'s a draw.</string>
<string name="surrenderwin">Your opponent surrenders. You win!</string>
<string name="surrenderlose">You surrender...</string>
<string name="surrenderdraw">You both surrender.</string>

<string name="menu_spells">Spells</string>
<string name="menu_about">About</string>

<string name="empty_left_hand">[Left Hand]</string>
<string name="empty_right_hand">[Right Hand]</string>

<string name="heading_spells"><u><b>Spells</b></u>\n</string>
<string name="heading_gestures"><u><b>Gestures (Left Hand)</b></u>\n</string>
<string name="emptyspellbook">\n\n\nYou don\'t know any spells yet.</string>
<string name="button_close">Close</string>
<string name="ins_righthand">\nDraw the mirror image for the right hand.\n</string>
<string name="stabdesc">(Not a spell.) Attack target for 1 damage.</string>
<string name="Pdesc">Prevents all physical damage: stabs, monster attacks, and missiles.</string>
<string name="SDdesc">Fire projectile at target for 1 damage.</string>
<string name="WFPdesc">2 magical damage to target. Ignores Shield.</string>
<string name="SFWdesc">Summon goblin to serve target spellcaster, or target monster's controller. A goblin can do 1 damage, and has 1 hit point.</string>
<string name="DFWdesc">Restore up to 1 health.</string>
<string name="DSFdesc">Target spellcaster must select same gesture for both hands. Target monster attacks its controller. Cancels with other psychological spells.</string>
<string name="PSDFdesc">Control target spellcaster's hand next turn. No effect on monsters. Cancels with other psychological spells.</string>
<string name="WWPdesc">4-turn Shield.</string>

<string name="PSFWdesc">Ogres can do 2 damage, and have 2 hit points.</string>
<string name="SWDdesc">Target can only gesture P K or W next turn. Cancels with other psychological spells.</string>
<string name="DPPdesc">Target wizard must repeat gestures. Target monster attacks same target. Cancels with other psychological spells.</string>
<string name="WPPdesc">Target is immune to all spells except Dispel Magic and Finger of Death.</string>
<string name="WWSdesc">Alternate sequence for Counter-spell</string>
<string name="PDWPdesc">Removes all enchantments from target wizard. Unsummon target monster, who can still attack this round.</string>
<string name="DFFDDdesc">5 electrical damage. Ignores Shield.</string>
<string name="SPFPdesc">Interrupt spell combo. Starting next turn, target wizard must start spells anew.</string>
<string name="FFFdesc">Target monster cannot attack next turn. Freeze target hand of wizard: F, S, W become C, D, P respectively. If already paralyzed, the same hand is paralyzed again, otherwise the caster chooses the hand. Cancels with other psychological spells.</string>
<string name="FPSFWdesc">Trolls can do 3 damage, and have 3 hit points.</string>
<string name="cDPWdesc">No other spells can be cast this turn. Unsummon all monsters, who still attack this round, and remove all enchantments. Global effect: works even when aimed at nothing. Shields target if valid.</string>
<string name="WPFDdesc">3 magical damage to target. Ignores <i>Shield</i>.</string>
<string name="DFPWdesc">Heal up to 2 health points. Cures disease.</string>
<string name="DSFFFcdesc">Target dies within 6 turns from disease. Can be cured with <i>Remove Enchantment</i>, <i>Cure Heavy Wounds</i> or <i>Dispel Magic</i>.</string>
<string name="FSSDDdesc">5 fire damage (ignores <i>Shield</i>). Protects target in an Ice Storm.</string>
<string name="cwdesc">Spells cast at target are reflected back at caster.</string>

<string name="WFPSFWdesc">Giants can do 4 damage, and have 4 hit points.</string>
<string name="DWWFWDdesc">Target dies within 6 turns from poison. Can be cured with <i>Remove Enchantment</i> or <i>Dispel Magic</i>.</string>
<string name="WWFPdesc">Target becomes immune to damage from <i>Fireball</i>, <i>Fire Storm</i> and <i>Fire Elementals</i> until enchantment is removed. Destroys <i>Fire Elementals</i>.</string>
<string name="SSFPdesc">Target becomes immune to damage from <i>Ice Storm</i> and <i>Ice Elementals</i> until enchantment is removed. Destroys <i>Ice Elementals</i>.</string>
<string name="SWWcdesc">Each being takes 5 fire damage unless protected by Resist Heat or Counter-spell. Cancels <i>Ice Storm</i> and <i>Ice Elemental</i>, merges with <i>Fire Storm</i>, absorbs <i>Fire Elemental</i>.</string>
<string name="WSScdesc">Each being takes 5 fire damage unless protected by Resist Heat or Counter-spell, or is hit by a Fireball. Cancels <i>Ice Storm</i> and <i>Ice Elemental</i>, merges with <i>Fire Storm</i>, absorbs <i>Fire Elemental</i>.</string>
<string name="PWPFSSSDdesc">Target dies, even if protected by Counter-spell. Ignores Shield.</string>

<string name="servererror">Cannot connect to server :(</string>
<string name="badport">Bad port number given.</string>

<string name="oppmoved">Opponent has moved. Tap to continue.</string>

<string name="about"><b>Spell Tap</b>\n<i>Ben Lynn</i>\n\n
http://cs.stanford.edu/~blynn/spelltap/
\n\nAdaption of Richard Bartle\'s <i>Spellbinder</i>, aka <i>Waving Hands</i>: http://www.mud.co.uk/richard/spellbnd.htm
</string>
</resources>
